Okay, let's talk a little bit about scoring.
Well, a "miss", a miss is 1 through 9 and that's what you get, two balls, and whatever you get, 1 through 9, that's what it will count, 7...7.
Okay, now also we'll look at the scoreboard and you'll get a spare.
Now, a spare, you'll see, see a strike and a spare.
So I got a 9 and a spare, you see there's 20.
Now, a spare counts as 10, whatever I get on my first ball, which I got a strike which is 10 pins, so it's 40.
It's 20 plus the 10 for the spare, plus the 10 pins I got on my first ball, becomes 40.
Then I got a strike, then I got a "double".
A double is two strikes in a row.
Then I got a triple, which is also called a "Turkey", some terminology there.
Now a Turkey is the highest you can get in one frame, 30 pins in one frame.
If you get 30 pins in the first, and 30 pins all the way through to the 12th frame, or the 10th frame, 300!
It's the object of the game, perfection!
300..twelve strikes in a row...go and get one!
Now let's talk a little bit more about scoring.
Let's go to the other side.
Now you see 9 was the first ball, and then they got that one pin that was left, which is a spare.
Then they got, on their first ball, a 9, so you add the spare which is 10, and the first ball which is 9, is 19 in the first frame.
They missed that one pin which is an "open", "miss", "open", same terminology.
So, add 9 onto 19, 28.
Same thing in the next frame, 9, miss, 8, miss, 45.
Alright, when you're scoring, sometimes they don't have computers and you have to manually score it.
So, if you get a strike, "X", if you get a 9, "9", if you make that pin, spare, slash ("/").
Open, as you saw on the computer, is just a line, a dash ("-").
Now if you throw a split, well, that's 8 and a big zero which means a hole or a split.
It's nice to put a slash spare through that split.